punahou.edu 2019-04-13

# Privacy and Terms - Punahou School

  * Privacy Policy
  * Terms of Use
  * GDPR

## Privacy Policy

Punahou School respects the privacy of every individual who visits this website. This Privacy Policy outlines the information that Punahou School may collect and how that information mat be used. The school reserves the right to alter this policy at any time by posting a new privacy policy at this location.

## Definition

The Punahou School website is defined as publicly accessible and password/login protected pages hosted under the domain punahou.edu.

Punahou School is not responsible for the privacy practices of external sites linked from or referenced by punahou.edu. This policy applies solely to information collected by this website.

## Personal Data

Punahou School will not collect any personally identifiable information about you, such as name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address ("personal data") through this site unless you have provided it voluntarily. If you do not want your personal data collected, do not submit it.

When you do provide personal data, that information may be used in the following ways, unless stated otherwise:

  * to fulfill a request you have made
  * to update your school maintained record
  * to contact you

The school will not sell, rent, or market personal data about you to third parties.

### Additional Information Collected Automatically

In some cases, this website may automatically (i.e., not via registration) collect information about you that is not personally identifiable. Examples of this type of information include the type of Internet browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, the IP address of your computer, and the domain name of the website from which you linked to this site. This information is used solely to provide the school with overall statistics on website usage, and to evaluate generalized user demographics.

### Information Placed Automatically on Your Computer - Cookies

When you view this website, some information may be stored on your computer. This information will be in the form of a "cookie" or similar file and willl allow the website to tailor the experience to your interests and preferences. With most Internet browsers, cookies can be blocked or erased after visiting a website. Some aspects of this website may not function properly if your browser is set to block cookies.

This website has enabled a Google advertising cookie, for the purpose of estimating demographic information about its visitors. Users may opt out of this Google advertising cookie by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

### Security

The school takes every precaution to protect users' information. When users submit sensitive information via this website, it is encrypted and remains secure during all stages of transmission. The school complies with all state and federal statutes requiring safeguards on specific types of information.

## Terms of Use

## Use Policy

www.punahou.edu is a private website that is intended for academic, administrative and community use by Punahou students, faculty, staff, current parents and alumni as well as interested members of the general public.

**By accessing www.punahou.edu, community participants agree to adhere to the following guidelines.**

These guidelines are provided to help website visitors ("participant") become aware of the responsibilities they are about to acquire. In general, these responsibilities include efficient, ethical and legal utilization of the network resources. **If a participant violates any of these provisions, his or her account will be terminated and/or appropriate legal action will be taken.**

## Terms and Conditions

1\. Acceptable Use

The use of this website must conform to its intended use. Transmission of any material in violation of any U.S. or state regulation is prohibited. This includes, but is not limited to: copyrighted material, threatening or obscene material, or material protected by [trademark](http://www.punahou.edu/trademarks/index.aspx) or trade secret. Use for commercial activities, product advertisement or political lobbying is prohibited.

2\. Warranties

The school makes no warranties of any kind, whether expressed or implied, for the service it is providing via this website. The school will not be responsible for any damages you suffer. This includes loss of data resulting from delays, non-deliveries, mis-deliveries or service interruptions. Use of any information obtained via this website is at your own risk. This website is provided as a service of convenience, and the school does not assume responsibility for the accuracy or quality of information within this website.

3\. Vandalism

Vandalism will result in cancellation of privileges. Vandalism is defined as any malicious attempt to harm or destroy hardware, software or data of the School or of another user, the Internet, or any other network that is connected to the Internet. This includes, but not limited to, the creation or uploading of computer viruses.

## GDPR

Punahou School ("Punahou") is committed to supporting the privacy of Punahou students, alumni and friends. This Privacy Statement explains how we handle and use the personal information we collect about our alumni, donors and other constituents. 

## What personal information we collect

While specific information may vary for particular individuals, we may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal information about you, which includes:

  1. Basic biographic/contact information – home and business addresses, phone numbers, email addresses and social media contact information
  2. Demographic information – names, gender, birth and death dates, photograph, and ethnicity (solely if you choose to provide ethnic information)
  3. Student information from Punahou records – classes, teachers, deans, affiliations and clubs, awards, activities and sports participation
  4. Employment information – company names, job titles and industry information
  5. Family information – spouse/partner's name, children's names and birth dates, and other familial relationships
  6. Engagement information – event attendance, volunteer interests, organization affiliations, committee participation, awards and honors
  7. Donor information – information regarding any pledge or donation which is made, including wealth assessment information and indicators of your interest in giving
  8. Analytical electronic information – aggregated information related to web visitor activity and email marketing actions

## How we collect personal information about you

We collect information about our constituents from a variety of sources. A vast majority of the information we maintain is that which you have provided to us, either by updating your profile online, registering for an event, communicating with us or making a donation.

We may also augment the information we collect about you. Typically this would be from internet searches and/or third party sources, including but not limited to Iwave (PRO), Wealth Engine, public records, social media sites (such as Facebook, Twitter, and Linkedin), ConnectED and Punahou Connect.

## How we use your personal information

We use your personal information for a number of legitimate purposes all in support of the school and its mission. Specifically, we use your personal information to:

  1. Keep you updated with information about Punahou and alumni activities
  2. Conduct surveys, including alumni satisfaction, donation preferences and interests
  3. Provide alumni services, such as Punahou Connect
  4. Fundraise for particular Punahou initiatives or programs
  5. Send you information about volunteer activities and invite you to Punahou events in your area
  6. Conduct philanthropic preference research in order to understand alumni and supporters
  7. Perform administrative tasks for internal record keeping purposes
  8. Create and analyze aggregated (fully anonymized) information about our students, alumni, donor and other supporters for statistical research purposes in support of our educational mission.

If you have concerns about any of these purposes, or how we communicate with you, please contact us at Lschiff@punahou.edu. We will always respect a request by you to stop processing your personal information (subject to our legal obligations.)

## When we share your personal information

To perform the functions listed above, it may be necessary to share your personal information with volunteers. All individuals performing functions for us are informed regarding appropriate handling of your personal information and they sign confidentiality agreements. We may also share your personal information with third parties performing services under contract with us, also confidentially.

## How your information is stored and secured

Punahou uses risk-assessed administrative, technical and physical security measures to protect your personal information. Only authenticated users with specific permissions may access the data using a virtual private network. We use firewalls and regular monitoring to evaluate any attempts at accessing the systems without permission. We conduct an annual security audit of our systems.

## How long we keep your personal information

We consider our relationship with students, parents, alumni, faculty, staff, donors and other stakeholders to be lifelong. This means that we will maintain a record for you until such time as you tell us that you no longer wish us to keep in touch. You may also make changes to communication preferences through email to Lschiff@punahou.edu. 

## Rights for Individuals in the European Economic Area

You have the right in certain circumstances to (1) access your personal information; (2) to correct or erase information; (3) restrict processing; and (4) object to communications, direct marketing, or profiling. To the extent applicable, the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation provides further information about your rights. You also have the right to lodge complaints with your national or regional data protection authority.

If you are inclined to exercise these rights, we request an opportunity to discuss with you any concerns you may have. To protect the personal information we hold, we may also request further information to verify your identify when exercising these rights. Upon a request to erase information, we will maintain a core set of personal data to ensure we do not contact you inadvertently in the future, as well as any information necessary for Punahou archival purposes. We may also need to retain some financial information for legal purposes, including US IRS compliance. 

If you provide information directly to Punahou from the European Economic Area (EEA), you consent to the transfer of your personal information outside of the EEA to the United States. You understand that the current laws and regulations of the United States may not provide the same level of protection as the data and privacy laws and regulations of the EEA.

You are under no statutory or contractual obligation to provide any personal data to us (other than personal data provided in connection with your status as a Punahou student.)

## Additional Information

We may change this Privacy Statement from time to time. If we make any significant changes in the way we treat your personal information we will make this clear on our Punahou websites or by contacting you directly.

The controller for your personal information is Punahou. We can be contacted at LSchiff@punahou.edu.

**This policy was last updated MAY 24, 2018.**
